[
  {
    "question": "Who was the first man to travel into space twice?",
    "answer1": "Gus Grissom",
    "answer2": "Yuri Gagarin",
    "answer3": "Michal Collins",
    "answer4": "Vladimir Titov",
    "correctAnswer": "Gus Grissom"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a butterfly, not a moth?",
    "answer1": "Speckled Wood",
    "answer2": "Burnished Brass",
    "answer3": "Red Underwing",
    "answer4": "Mother Shipton",
    "correctAnswer": "Speckled Wood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which king was married to Eleanor of Aquitaine?",
    "answer1": "Henry II",
    "answer2": "Richard I",
    "answer3": "James III",
    "answer4": "Edward II",
    "correctAnswer": "Henry II"
  },
  {
    "question": "On February 22, 1989, what group won the first Grammy award for Best Hard Rock/Metal Performance?",
    "answer1": "Jethro Tull",
    "answer2": "AC/DC",
    "answer3": "Metallica",
    "answer4": "Living Color",
    "correctAnswer": "Jethro Tull"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following pieces of currency was the first to use the motto \"In God We Trust\"?",
    "answer1": "Two-cent piece",
    "answer2": "Nickel",
    "answer3": "One dollar bill",
    "answer4": "Five dollar bill",
    "correctAnswer": "Two-cent piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "Playwright Anton Chekhov graduated from the University of Moscow with a degree in what?",
    "answer1": "Medicine",
    "answer2": "Law",
    "answer3": "Philosophy",
    "answer4": "Economics",
    "correctAnswer": "Medicine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before the American colonies switched to the Gregorian calendar, on what date did their new year start?",
    "answer1": "25.Mar",
    "answer2": "01.Jul",
    "answer3": "24.Dec",
    "answer4": "31.Oct",
    "correctAnswer": "25.Mar"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the U.S., the Sony Walkman personal cassette player was originally marketed in 1979 under what name?",
    "answer1": "Soundabout",
    "answer2": "Listener",
    "answer3": "Eardrummer",
    "answer4": "Music Box",
    "correctAnswer": "Soundabout"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the only winner of the Nobel Peace Prize to decline the prize?",
    "answer1": "Le Duc Tho",
    "answer2": "Andrei Sakharov",
    "answer3": "Aung San Suu Kyi",
    "answer4": "Albert Schweitzer",
    "correctAnswer": "Le Duc Tho"
  },
  {
    "question": "People who have a marked physical reaction to beautiful art are said to suffer from what syndrome?",
    "answer1": "Stendhal's Syndrome",
    "answer2": "Beckett's Syndrome",
    "answer3": "Proust Syndrome",
    "answer4": "Jerusalem Syndrome",
    "correctAnswer": "Stendhal's Syndrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the only Nobel laureate to win an Academy Award?",
    "answer1": "George Bernard Shaw",
    "answer2": "Jean-Paul Sartre",
    "answer3": "Toni Morrison",
    "answer4": "John Steinback",
    "correctAnswer": "George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Famous pediatrician and author Dr. Benjamin Spock won an Olympic gold medal in what sport?",
    "answer1": "Rowing",
    "answer2": "Swimming",
    "answer3": "Sailing",
    "answer4": "Fencing",
    "correctAnswer": "Rowing"
  },
  {
    "question": "During WWII, U.S. soldiers used the first commercial aerosol cans to hold what?",
    "answer1": "Insecticide",
    "answer2": "Antiseptic",
    "answer3": "Cleaning fluid",
    "answer4": "Shaving cream",
    "correctAnswer": "Insecticide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did artist Grant Wood use as the model for the farmer in his classic painting \"American Gothic\"?",
    "answer1": "His dentist",
    "answer2": "Local sheriff",
    "answer3": "His butcher",
    "answer4": "Traveling salesman",
    "correctAnswer": "His dentist"
  },
  {
    "question": "Khrushchev's famous 1960 \"shoe-banging\" outburst at the U.N. was in response to a delegate from what nation?",
    "answer1": "The Philippines",
    "answer2": "Australia",
    "answer3": "The Netherlands",
    "answer4": "Turkey",
    "correctAnswer": "The Philippines"
  },
  {
    "question": "What great thinker's death is attributed to a chill he caught while stuffing a chicken with snow for an experiment on refrigeration?",
    "answer1": "Francis Bacon",
    "answer2": "Pythagoras",
    "answer3": "Archimedes",
    "answer4": "Isaac Newton",
    "correctAnswer": "Francis Bacon"
  },
  {
    "question": "A rare example of a word that rhymes with \"orange,\" the Blorenge is a what?",
    "answer1": "Mountain in Wales",
    "answer2": "Forest in Scotland",
    "answer3": "River in Ireland",
    "answer4": "Desert in Australia",
    "correctAnswer": "Mountain in Wales"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to his career as an astrologer and \"prophet,\" Nostradamus published a 1555 treatise that included a section on what?",
    "answer1": "Making jams and jellies",
    "answer2": "Digging graves",
    "answer3": "Cheating at card games",
    "answer4": "Training parrots to talk",
    "correctAnswer": "Making jams and jellies"
  },
  {
    "question": "When scientists tested it with an electroencephalogram, which of these food items produced readings similar to a human brain?",
    "answer1": "Lime Jell-O",
    "answer2": "Wint-O-Green Life Saver",
    "answer3": "SPAM",
    "answer4": "Jet-Puffed Marshmallow",
    "correctAnswer": "Lime Jell-O"
  }
]
